PHOEBE ARROWSMITH

Greater London phoebearrowsmith@gmail.com

I recently graduated from the University of Exeter with a 2:1 in Computer Science and Mathematics. Having completed several computer science modules including software development, object-oriented programming, and database theory and design, I have a good understanding and experience of algorithms, data structures and programming languages. Additionally learning core mathematical topics such as differential equations, linear algebra and mathematical methods and structures has developed my problem-solving, analytical thinking and logical reasoning skills.

EDUCATION

September 2020 – July 2023 University of Exeter

Computer Science and Mathematics BSc, 2:1

September 2018 – March 2020 Glyn School, Epsom A-levels

Mathematics, A Biology, B Sociology, B

September 2013 – June 2018 Rosebery School, Epsom GCSEs

Mathematics, 8 English Literature, 6 Sociology, A Combined Science: Trilogy, 9-8 Statistics, B Spanish, 5 English Language, 7 History, 6 Textiles, A*

UNIVERSITY PROJECTS

WEB APPLICATION

For my final year dissertation project, I developed a web application that leveraged machine learning to help users identify potential food intolerances by analysing their food diary and symptom log data. The machine learning algorithm was developed in Python and analysed the users' data and identified any patterns or correlations between food and symptoms and these correlations were persisted in a MySql database. The use of Generative Adversarial Networks (GAN) was explored to generate high volumes of data for testing. I developed a user-friendly web application with functionality to allow users to create a login where they could record their individual food diary and symptom log; the app also fed back the predicted food intolerances based on the correlation for users' diet. The user interface was developed using HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript and the Bootstrap framework was employed to facilitate streamlined front-end development.

WEB APPLICATION GAME

For one of my group project tasks, I helped develop a mobile web app game that encouraged students to go onto campus and engage with new people. Once logged in, the user would be

presented with a map of the university campus. Every user was assigned to a team depending on which college they were in (e.g. Humanities or The Business School). They then had to earn points by physically staying for a long time at campus buildings (shown as castles on the map) and their movements were tracked using their phone location. The points earned would then be displayed on the weekly and all-time leaderboards. The college and the person with the most points would win the game. My teammate and I worked on the front-end part of this projects where we took a mobile-first approach and developed web pages and components to make the game engaging and user friendly. We used HTML, CSS and JavaScript. We also used Figma to design the user interface.

ANDROID MOBILE APPLICATION

As a project for my module on Mobile and Ubiquitous computing, I developed an Android mobile application to help users find cocktails they could make based on their preferred spirits, e.g. vodka, gin, whiskey etc. When the user first selected the app, they were presented with five different spirits. They then selected one or more from the list. An open-source API was called which returned a list of cocktails that use the spirit(s) they've entered. By clicking on a cocktail, the user is directed to a web page displaying information on the full recipe and the glass type. I used Android Studio as the IDE along with Java and XML.

WEBSITE

For my module on Web Development, I developed a website that would inform a user if they had a connection to a person infected with COVID-19. Once logged in, a user was able to add new places they'd visited, report an infection and adjust the alert distance and time span for which the contact tracing would be performed. To do this I used HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Ajax, Sessions and Cookies.

EXPERIENCE

OCTOBER 2023 - JANURARY 2024

TEMPORARY ADMINISTRATOR, EPSOM AND EWELL BOROUGH COUNCIL

I have recently completed a temporary contract working as an administrator for the operations department within Epsom and Ewell Council. During the first two months, I worked with the waste management team where I used Microsoft Excel and Word to regularly update the system and create reminders. Additionally, I managed complaint cases on the CRM database. After this, I worked with the allotment team, including plot allocation and complaint management.

JUNE 2022 – SEPTEMBER 2022

BARTENDER/WAITRESS ROLE, THE LEATHERHEAD GOLF CLUB

I worked full time at the Leatherhead Golf Club, where I served drinks and food in the clubhouse. Working in a fast-paced environment, I developed the ability to handle multiple tasks while maintaining a friendly and professional demeanor. I also assisted with hosting and serving at various events held at the golf club, which required a more formal style of service. This experience strengthened my communication skills and taught me the importance of team working and attention to detail.

JULY 2019

OFFICE INTERN, BERKLEY HOMES

As part of my school's work experience initiative, I secured a short-term placement as an office intern at Berkley Group. During that time, I worked in many different departments around the office.

- Assisting the Accounting department, where I updated the billings and payroll costs for a smaller arm of the company. I gained valuable skills in data management and data entry, whilst further improving my Excel knowledge.
- I spent some of my time on the placement helping the software developers. I gained experience using Visio, built on my technical knowledge and developed my teamwork skills
- Manning the office's IT helpdesk. I was responsible for referring employees in need of IT
 assistance to relevant engineers. I also managed the ticket logs, providing a daily audit
 trial of the issues and resolutions seen each day. By engaging with customers, I was able
 to develop my skills in a customer facing environment.

JANURARY 2019 - MAY 2019

PRIVATE TUTOR

I privately tutored students. I taught students of multiple levels, from SATs to GCSEs. I mainly helped with subjects such as Mathematics and the Sciences.

I built on my previously developed mentoring experience and gained skills in one-on-one teaching and in how to engage and encourage students.

SEPTEMBER 2018 – JUNE 2019

ASSISSTANT TUTOR, GLYN SCHOOL

During my first year of sixth form, I was selected to work as a tutoring assistant at the school. I was part of a group of tutors teaching classes of children from all ages across a wide range of subjects. This experience helped me improve my communication and team working skills.

VOLUNTEER WORK

PUBLICITY SECRETARY – EXETER UNIVERSITY MATHS SOCIETY

I created engaging content for the society's social media platforms to inform members of the upcoming social events and academic talks. I also contributed to the overall growth and development of the society by actively participating in weekly meetings to offer ideas for improvement. I enjoyed the creative aspect of making new posts for social media and working as a team to host different events.

BROWNIE UNIT VOLUNTEER

I assisted in running a Brownie unit, helping to supervise Brownies and run various activities. This role helped me to develop my communication and management skills.

HOBBIES

I joined the Exeter University Amateur Boxing Club society where I enjoyed learning the basics of boxing and picking up a new skill.

During lockdown, I decided to do golf lessons and have since really enjoyed continuing on what I've learnt and playing golf in my spare time.

During my time at Sixth Form, I was part of the netball team where I attended weekly training sessions and regularly competed in tournaments. I continued this at university where I joined the Exeter University Netball Club society.

Prior to Sixth Form, I was a member of the Sea Rangers, which is an organisation that provides girls the opportunity to get involved in water-based activities. At Sea Rangers I learnt to kayak, paddle board and sail achieving RYA level 4.